

Fritz Knack

Business Architect

Seeking

Business Architect or similar senior position where **Technology meets Business**.

Profile

I am a Business Architect with solid knowledge and experience with all the moving pieces in technology and business processes.

My particular strengths are communications, data flow, and troubleshooting. I have a remarkable talent for bridging the language gap between business and technology people.

Contact

resume@phrits.com

More

phrits.com/resume/

Summary and Skills

Experience in banking, telecommunications, and software production.

Strong background in databases, operating systems, and programming.

Hands-on experience with:

- business application lifecycle from concept to sunset
- **risk** awareness, analysis, and mitigation
- business process modeling, documentation, development, improvement, and implementation
- system administration, database administration, and integrated systems

Comfortable with **SQL**, Python, HTML, CSS, PHP, Perl, and MS-Office products. I can work with any C-like programming language.

Work Experience

Wells Fargo: 2000-20012, 2015-present

- Significantly improved the approach to reimplementing a set of critical systems, avoiding operational disruption while reducing complexity, duplication of effort, and overhead.
- Led the custom design, development, and deployment of corporate call and problem tracking software using Remedy ARS and DSO.
- Developed and maintained near real-time interfaces for automatic vendor dispatching from the enterprise help desk system. Bulletproof for over 5 years.

Food Service Sabbatical, 2012-2015

 Washed dishes, cleaned grill hoods, sliced beef, cooked grits, made soups and salsa, and catered a 10,000 square foot facility.

Nortel Networks, 1998-2000

One-man Remedy ARS shop: System and database administrator, application design, development, custom integration, maintenance, and support.
Zero unscheduled downtime.

CONXUS Communications, Inc., 1996 – 1998

 Produced company-wide sales and churn reports consolidating multiple sources in the days before federated database reporting.

Education

UNCC-Trilogy Boot Camp

Radford University

Data Analytics & Visualization Certificate, 2023

B.S. Mathematics, 1993

Last updated: 2023-03-01